准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
督导队员
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
泡芙老师滑浪学校
Mrs. Puff's Boating School
滑浪学校
勤奋的学生们学习交通规则的地方
where diligent students learn the rules of the road
同学们  把书放下
Everyone, put down your books
因为今天要选出
because it's time to pick out
今日督导队员了
the hall monitor of the day
来看看
Let's see here
本周的督导队员是
This week's hall monitor will be
巴特  吉米
Bart, Jimmy
不对
No, no
蒂娜  拉尔夫
Tina, Ralph
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
是吉米
It's Jimmy
吉米是督导队员
Jimmy's the hall monitor
泡芙老师  我已经当过了
Mrs. Puff, I've done it already
菲尔
Phil?
我不当  泡芙老师
No way, Mrs. Puff
蒂娜
Tina--
你来当督导队员
You're the hall monitor
我已经当过三遍了
I've done it three times already
贝丝
Beth
她都毕业了
She graduated
亨利
Henry
维拉
Vera
克雷顿
Clayton
好吧  看来没得选了
All right, I guess I have no choice
今日督导队员就是
The hall monitor of the day is
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
督导队员海绵宝宝报到  老师
Hall monitor SpongeBob reporting for duty, ma'am
我准备好担任督导校园的职务了
I'm ready to assume my position in the hall
我会保护好校园的弱势群体
I will protect all that are weak in the hall
在校园里  一切规则都会严格实行
All rules will be enforced in the hall
好
Okay
戴好帽子和腰带
Just take the hat and belt
我还不能戴  老师
I can't accept that yet, ma'am
我首先要致辞
First, I have to make my speech
非得这么麻烦是吗
You can't make this easy, can you?
同学们
Classmates
我究竟凭什么能配得上这样大的荣誉
Who am I to deserve such a great honor?
没了泡芙老师  我什么都不是
Why, I would be nothing without Mrs. Puff
饶了我吧
Give me a break
我对老百姓们说的话  只有心中的感动
And to my public, all I can say is I'm touched
此外  我将会执行好我的任务
And furthermore, I will carry out my duties
罪过与处罚
Crime and punishment
校园里的处罚与罪过
punishment and crime in the hall
都让我想到有史以来最好的督导队员
which reminds me of an extremely long speech
所写的超长致辞里的话
written by the greatest hall monitor of all time
朋友们  同学们  少年犯们
"Friends, students, juvenile delinquents
请听我说
lend me your ears"
总而言之  一刻也不能耽搁
In conclusion and without a moment to spare
我将穿上这制服  尽职尽责当好一名
I will put on this uniform and assume my duties as
督导队员
Hall monitor
祝我好运  泡芙老师
Wish me luck, Mrs. Puff
我会
And I will be
海绵宝宝  你没事吧
SpongeBob, are you okay?
我演讲又太长了吗
I overdid the speech again, didn't I?
恐怕是这样
I'm afraid so
真该死
Tartar sauce
看来这玩意我用不上了
I guess I won't be needing this
我几乎还没了解你
I hardly knew ye
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
怎么了  泡芙老师
Yes, Mrs. Puff?
我可以再让你穿到明天
I can at least let you wear it until tomorrow
谢谢泡芙老师
Thanks, Mrs. Puff
我刚刚做的事会有什么后果
What are the consequences of what I've just done?
督导
Hall
队员
Monitor
红绿灯坏了
Broken traffic light
是谁说我的督导任务
Who's to say my monitor duties
在下课铃响后就要结束了
should end just because the bell rang?
我到哪都能帮得上忙
I can be helpful anywhere
这个一看就是督导队员的职责所在
This looks like a job for the hall monitor
这座城没了你要怎么办  海绵宝宝
What would this town do without you, SpongeBob?
我的腿
My legs
在巡逻
On patrol
我在巡逻
I'm on patrol
敞开着的窗户
An open window
再来点海藻杂烩好吗  亲爱的
More seaweed medley, dear?
这些笨蛋
The fools
他们让自己身处危险之中
They've left themselves susceptible to danger
我必须指出他们这样有什么错误
I must show them the error of their ways
用实例说明
through example
我是开窗疯子
I'm the open window maniac
希望你们学到了宝贵的教训
I hope you learned a valuable lesson
在巡逻
On patrol
我在巡逻
I'm on patrol
破坏公物
Vandals
又一桩罪案
Another crime
草莓味
Strawberry
必须立刻行动
I must act
派大星
Patrick
我的冰淇淋
My ice cream--
活过来了
It's alive
派大星  在这下面
Patrick, down here
海绵宝宝  是你啊
Oh, SpongeBob, it's you
派大星  快下来
Patrick, come down here
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我在这下面
I'm down here
你看着好奇怪
You look funny
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
要叫督导队员
That's "hall monitor" to you
抱歉  警官
Sorry, officer
道歉还远远不够  派大星
Sorry's not good enough, Patrick
你刚才犯了罪  我要逮捕你
You've just committed a crime and I'm taking you in
什么罪
What crime?
我是个坏人
I'm a bad person
号外  号外
Extra, extra
疯子袭击裤头村
Maniac strikes bikini bottom
全城居民人心惶惶
City paralyzed with fear
疯子袭击裤头村
来一份吧  朋友
Take it, friends
增广见闻保护自己
Arm yourselves with knowledge
号外号外
Extra, extra
疯子
"Maniac
裤头村
bikini bottom
车祸
car wrecks
私闯民宅
break-in"
还有谁能胜任把疯子绳之以法的任务
Who better to bring this maniac to justice
比得过我
than me
督导队员
the hall monitor
可我一个人处理不来这个案子
But I can't handle this case alone
派大星  想结束犯罪生活吗
Patrick, are you ready to give up your life of crime?
我想当好人
I want to be good
现在你只要一个授权标志
Now you just need a symbol of authority
完美
Perfect
逮捕疯子让他绳之以法是我们的职责
It is our duty to catch this maniac
and bring him to justice
可是要怎么做
But how to proceed?
听好  副手警官
Listen, deputy
你可是个前任罪犯
You're an ex-criminal--
你会做什么
What would you do?
我会去买冰淇淋
I'd get an ice cream
冰淇淋
好了  现在做什么
Okay, now what?
冰淇淋
根本没用
This isn't working
必须做出点别的事
We've got to do something else
带对讲机做的事
Something with walkie-talkies
职责在召唤着我
And now duty calls
好了副手警官  我往那走
All right, deputy, I'll go that way
你往另一边走
you go some different way
驱逐他们
Run ‘em out
下午好  小朋友
Afternoon, son
你们好  兄弟俩
Hello, brothers
小朋友  我们在找疯子
Son, we're looking for the maniac
你见到过这个人吗
Have you seen this man?
通缉
疯子
是那个疯子
It's the maniac
把他拿开
Take him away
冷静点  小朋友
Calm down, son
这只是幅画
It's just a drawing
不是真的
not the real thing
现在我们要再给你看这幅画
Now we're going to show you this picture again
跟我们说你有没有见到过这人
and you'll tell us if you've seen this guy
明白了吗
understand?
明白
Yeah
好
Okay
好可怕
Horrible
待家里别出来  小朋友
Stay indoors, son
把头上的甜筒拿下来
And take that cone off your head
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
请回答  海绵宝宝
Come in, SpongeBob
通缉
疯子
快回复
Answer
我是海绵宝宝  派大星
SpongeBob here, Patrick
请讲
Report
我再也不想当警察了
I don't want to be a policeman anymore
我好怕
I'm scared
保持冷静  副手警官
Get a hold of yourself, deputy
我好想回家
I want to go home
可怜的小子
Poor rookie
好了  我要回去了
All right, I'm on my way back
快点  海绵宝宝
Hurry, SpongeBob
天好像快要
I think it's getting
黑了
dark
警笛打开  我会到你那的
Just put on your siren, I'll be right there
通缉
疯子
海绵宝宝  我看到他了
SpongeBob, I see him
他在哪  派大星
Where is he, Patrick?
在贝壳街和珊瑚大道的路口
At the intersection of conch and coral
贝壳街
珊瑚大道
我就在那
That's where I am
他就在我附近  可我看不到
He's right on top of me, but I can't see him
他在干什么
What's he doing?
他就站在那  不怀好意
He's just standing there, menacingly
快离开那  海绵宝宝
Get out of there, SpongeBob
疯子开始尖叫了
That's his maniac shriek
他就要攻击了
He's going to attack
他在发癫
He's acting all crazy
快跑
Run
躲在那栋楼后边
Hide behind that building
不  他就在那栋楼后边
No, he's behind that building
快  躲在那个路牌后边
Quick, hide behind that street sign
不  别走
No, wait
那个疯子就在那路牌后边
The maniac just went behind that sign
快  到路灯底下去
Quick, get under the street light
不  别去
No, wait
他也在那
He's there, too
快逃命吧
Run for your life
重复一遍  副手警官
Say again, deputy?
那个疯子在信箱里
The maniac's in the mailbox
这位长得也不像当疯子的料啊
This guy's not half-bad-looking for a maniac
等一下  派大星
Wait a minute, Patrick
我就是那个疯子
I'm the maniac
通缉
疯子
我们会把这个作为呈堂证供
We'll take that as a confession
海绵宝宝  你在这啊
SpongeBob SquarePants, there you are
我放任你一分钟不管
I turn my back on you for one minute
你就毁掉了大半座城市
and you destroy half the city
你应该为自己感到羞耻
You should be ashamed of yourself
你认识这个人
You know this guy?
当然认识了
Of course, I do
一开始就是我给他的这套制服
I'm the one who gave him the uniform in the first place
我要为他负责
He's my responsibility
总而言之  同学们
And in conclusion, students
红灯停  绿灯行
red means stop, green means go
海绵宝宝
And SpongeBob
怎么了  泡芙老师
Yes, Mrs. Puff?
下课到我这儿来面批
I'd like to see you after class
六个月以后过来
six months from now
水母狂欢节
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
啊  水母田
Ah, jellyfish fields
在这我们能看到海绵宝宝
Here we find SpongeBob
又一次在捕捉野生水母
once again stalking the wild jellyfish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
在哪
Hello?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
他应该就在这附近才对
He's supposed to be here somewhere
安全第一
Safety first
总算逮到你了
I finally got you
没有什么东西能比得过
There is nothing better than
来自天然水母的水母酱的味道
the taste of natural jelly from a jellyfish
再见了
See you later
我的眼镜
My glasses
谢了  小家伙
Thanks, little guy
拜
Bye
我不能再玩了  小水母
I can't play anymore, jellyfish
我得回家去
I got to get home
不行  你可不能跟我一起回家
No, you can't come home with me
小水母  你必须要待在这
Jellyfish, you've got to stay here
待在这
Stay
小水母  再说最后一次
Jellyfish, for the last time
你不能跟我一起回家
you cannot come home with me
管他呢
What the heck
章鱼哥
Squidward
章鱼老大哥
Squidwardiard
章鱼哥  快看我的新宠物
Squidward, look at my new pet
那不算宠物  那是野生动物
That's no pet, that's a wild animal
才不是
No, he isn't
瞧好了
Watch this
去捡
Fetch
我伸了多少根手指
How many fingers am I holding up?
装死
Play dead
逝者安息
我不会让那玩意进我家门的
I wouldn't let that thing in my house
就算它会自己上厕所也不行
even if it was potty-trained
用不着给我看
I didn't need to see that
我们要去我家玩一会儿
Well, we're going to my house to have a little fun
跟水母玩怎么可能会有意思
How can you possibly have fun with a jellyfish?
迪斯科  摇滚  流行     恶心     古典
我认识的人当中就只有海绵宝宝
SpongeBob is the only guy I know
会跟一只水母一块玩
that can have fun with a jellyfish
12个小时
for 12 hours
你真的好喜欢跳舞
You sure like to dance
行了  今晚玩够了
Well, that's enough for tonight
该上床睡觉了
It's time to go to bed
你这样不对  小家伙
You've got it all wrong, little fellow
上床
Bed
跟着我做
Repeat after me
上床
Bed
让你就待在这
We'll just keep you right here
别担心了  小蜗
Quit worrying, Gary
它不会出事的
He'll be just fine
大家晚安
Good night, everybody
小蜗
早安  小蜗
Good morning, Gary
早安  小水母
Good morning, jellyfish
小水母
Jellyfish?
过来  小水母
Here, jellyfish
水母
Oh, jelly
Jellyf --
你们都是打哪来的
Where'd you all come from?
好了  都够了
Okay, that's it
狂欢结束
Party is over
你们留得太久了
You guys have overstayed your welcome
音乐太吵了
This music is way too loud
好好笑
Very funny
我是认真的
I'm serious
十八小时了
Eighteen hours
我得给海绵宝宝来点颜色看看
I'm going to give that SpongeBob a piece of my mind
喂
Hello
海绵宝宝  给我听好
SpongeBob, listen to me
你这方头呆脑害我耳朵难受得很
you square-headed assault on my ears
我已经受够了
I've had enough of this
草莓味的
Strawberry
你这一套我也会
Two can play at this
各位  别玩了
Come on, guys, enough is enough
别激动
Take it easy
好  我去跟他谈谈
Okay, I'll talk to him
章鱼哥  你可不可以
Squidward, would it be possible
竖笛好好吹吗
to play your clarinet a little better?
我觉得水母好像不喜欢
I don't think the jellyfish like it
水母不喜欢
The jellyfish don't like
什
wha
好啊兄弟
why sure, pal
我会好好吹的
I can play better
行了  他说他会好好吹的
Okay, he said he'll play better
这可不算好好吹
That's not better
不要激动
Take it easy with that
等等
Wait--
我会调小声点的
I can turn it down
人人都好会批评
Everybody's a critic
以后你再也听不到我吹竖笛了
You won't be hearing from me anymore
这样可不好
Hey, now, that wasn't nice
行了  都够了
Okay, that is it
全都出去
Everybody out
等等
Wait
慢着
Hold on
等等
Wait
快上来  小蜗
Come on, Gary
小蜗  你说得对
Gary, you were right
谢谢你没有火上浇油
Thanks for not rubbing it in
他们停下了
They stopped?
小蜗  继续摇下去
Gary, don't stop shaking it
水母田
今天海绵宝宝学到了
Today SpongeBob has learned
一场海底最严酷的教训
one of the sea's harshest lessons--
野生动物会狂欢不止
wild animals can throw very wild parties
我感受得到
I felt that